[
  {
    "Question": "The Battle of Plassey was fought in",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1757,
    "Option B": 1782,
    "Option C": 1748,
    "Option D": 1764,
    "Correct Ans": 1757
  },
  {
    "Question": "The territory of Porus who offered strong resistance to Alexander was situated between the rivers of",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Sutlej and Beas",
    "Option B": "Jhelum and Chenab",
    "Option C": "Ravi and Chenab",
    "Option D": "Ganga and Yamuna",
    "Correct Ans": "Jhelum and Chenab"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Under Akbar, the Mir Bakshi was required to look after",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "military affairs",
    "Option B": "the state treasury",
    "Option C": "the royal household",
    "Option D": "the land revenue system",
    "Correct Ans": "military affairs"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Tripitakas are sacred books of",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Buddhists",
    "Option B": "Hindus",
    "Option C": "Jains",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    "Correct Ans": "Buddhists"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The trident-shaped symbol of Buddhism does not represent",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Nirvana",
    "Option B": "Sangha",
    "Option C": "Buddha",
    "Option D": "Dhamma",
    "Correct Ans": "Nirvana"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The theory of economic drain of India during British imperialism was propounded by",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
    "Option B": "Dadabhai Naoroji",
    "Option C": "R.C. Dutt",
    "Option D": "M.K. Gandhi",
    "Correct Ans": "Dadabhai Naoroji"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The treaty of Srirangapatna was signed between Tipu Sultan and",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Robert Clive",
    "Option B": "Cornwallis",
    "Option C": "Dalhousie",
    "Option D": "Warren Hastings",
    "Correct Ans": "Cornwallis"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The system of competitive examination for civil service was accepted in principle in the year",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1833,
    "Option B": 1853,
    "Option C": 1858,
    "Option D": 1882,
    "Correct Ans": 1853
  },
  {
    "Question": "Through which one of the following, the king exercised his control over villages in the Vijayanagar Empire?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Dannayaka",
    "Option B": "Sumanta",
    "Option C": "Nayaka",
    "Option D": "Mahanayakacharya",
    "Correct Ans": "Mahanayakacharya"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Vijayanagara ruler, Kirshnadev Raya's work Amuktamalyada, was in",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Telugu",
    "Option B": "Sanskrit",
    "Option C": "Tamil",
    "Option D": "Kannada",
    "Correct Ans": "Telugu"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where did ‘Tebhega’ movement occur in 1946?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Maharashtra",
    "Option B": "Tamil Nadu",
    "Option C": "Karnataka",
    "Option D": "Bengal",
    "Correct Ans": "Bengal"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the name of the Chinese pilgrim who visited during the reign of Harshavardhana?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Hiuen Tsang",
    "Option B": "Fahein",
    "Option C": "Hiuen Tsang",
    "Option D": "None of the Above",
    "Correct Ans": "Hiuen Tsang"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where did the formation of Azad Hind Fauj take Place?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Thailand",
    "Option B": "Singapore",
    "Option C": "Russia",
    "Option D": "Germany",
    "Correct Ans": "Singapore"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first emperor of the Maurya Empire?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Chandragupta Maurya",
    "Option B": "Ashoka the Great",
    "Option C": "Samudragupta",
    "Option D": "Harsha",
    "Correct Ans": "Chandragupta Maurya"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Mughal Empire reached its peak under the rule of which emperor?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Babur",
    "Option B": "Akbar",
    "Option C": "Shah Jahan",
    "Option D": "Aurangzeb",
    "Correct Ans": "Akbar"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which one of the following was the capital of Kosala?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Sravasti",
    "Option B": "Shuktimati",
    "Option C": "Kaushambi",
    "Option D": "Indraprastha",
    "Correct Ans": "Sravasti"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is the excavator of Harappa site?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Daya ram sahni",
    "Option B": "Rakhal das Bannerji",
    "Option C": "Mackey",
    "Option D": "B.K. Thapar",
    "Correct Ans": "Daya ram sahni"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The local name of Mohenjodaro is:",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Mould of the living",
    "Option B": "Mould of the tree",
    "Option C": "Mould of the dead",
    "Option D": "Mould of the survivor",
    "Correct Ans": "Mould of the dead"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the last great ruler of Gupta dynasty?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Skandagupta",
    "Option B": "Kumaragupta I",
    "Option C": "Chandragupta II",
    "Option D": "None Of these",
    "Correct Ans": "Skandagupta"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following are two works of Kalidasa?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Raghuvamsha and Kiratarjuniya",
    "Option B": "Kumara Sambhav and Raghuvamsha",
    "Option C": "Malti Madhava and Kumara Sambhava",
    "Option D": "Malti Madhav and Kumara Sambhava",
    "Correct Ans": "Kumara Sambhav and Raghuvamsha"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first Indo-Greek king, who became Buddhist?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Antiochus II",
    "Option B": "Apollodotus I",
    "Option C": "Apollodotus II",
    "Option D": "Menander II",
    "Correct Ans": "Menander II"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who among the following built the Gomateshwara statue at Sravanabelagola ?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Chandragupta Maurya",
    "Option B": "Kharvela",
    "Option C": "Amoghavarsha",
    "Option D": "Chamundaraya",
    "Correct Ans": "Chamundaraya"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which type of pottery was most popular with the Later Vedic people?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Black-slipped Ware",
    "Option B": "Black and Red Ware",
    "Option C": "Painted Grey Ware",
    "Option D": "Red Ware",
    "Correct Ans": "Red Ware"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Veda that contains charms and spells toward off evils and diseases is",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Rigveda",
    "Option B": "Atharvaveda",
    "Option C": "Samaveda",
    "Option D": "Yajurveda",
    "Correct Ans": "Atharvaveda"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The most famous Chera ruler was",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Udiyanjeral",
    "Option B": "Nedunjeraladan",
    "Option C": "Senguttuvan",
    "Option D": "Sengannan",
    "Correct Ans": "Senguttuvan"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following was not one of the ruling dynasties of South India in the Sangam Age?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Chola",
    "Option B": "Chera",
    "Option C": "Pandya",
    "Option D": "Pallava",
    "Correct Ans": "Pallava"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Harappan weapons were made of",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "stone",
    "Option B": "copper",
    "Option C": "bronze",
    "Option D": "all the above",
    "Correct Ans": "all the above"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following Gupta emperors is represented his coins as playing the lute or Veena?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Chandragupta-I",
    "Option B": "Chandragupta-II",
    "Option C": "Samudragupta",
    "Option D": "Skandagupta",
    "Correct Ans": "Samudragupta"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is the author of Vikramakacharita?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Ravi Kirti",
    "Option B": "Mangalesa",
    "Option C": "Bana",
    "Option D": "Bilhana",
    "Correct Ans": "Bilhana"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the founder of the Satavahana dynasty?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Sri Satakarni",
    "Option B": "Simuka",
    "Option C": "Pulumayi-I",
    "Option D": "Yajnasri Satakarni",
    "Correct Ans": "Simuka"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the founder of the Kanva dynasty?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Suserman",
    "Option B": "Vishnusarma",
    "Option C": "Vassudeva",
    "Option D": "Vasumitra",
    "Correct Ans": "Vassudeva"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who among the following rulers was first to embrace Buddhism?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Ashoka",
    "Option B": "Ajatasatru",
    "Option C": "Bindusara",
    "Option D": "Bimbisara",
    "Correct Ans": "Ashoka"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Rathas of Mahabalipuram, the rock- cut architecture, were built by a king of the dynasty of",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Chola",
    "Option B": "Hoysala",
    "Option C": "Pallava",
    "Option D": "Rashtrakuta",
    "Correct Ans": "Pallava"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the capital of the early Chalukyas?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Badami",
    "Option B": "Kalyani",
    "Option C": "Kanchi",
    "Option D": "Vengi",
    "Correct Ans": "Badami"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the ancient name of river Satulaj?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Askini",
    "Option B": "Vitasta",
    "Option C": "Shutodri",
    "Option D": "Parushni",
    "Correct Ans": "Shutodri"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the founder of Pataliputra?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Bimbisar",
    "Option B": "Ajatashatru",
    "Option C": "Udayin",
    "Option D": "Kanishka",
    "Correct Ans": "Udayin"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is known as the Napoleon of India?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Srigupta",
    "Option B": "Chandragupta",
    "Option C": "Samudragupta",
    "Option D": "Devicharangupta",
    "Correct Ans": "Samudragupta"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who wrote Si- Yu- ki?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Harshavardhan",
    "Option B": "Selucas Nicator",
    "Option C": "Hieun Tsiang",
    "Option D": "Megasthanese",
    "Correct Ans": "Hieun Tsiang"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the founder of Vikramshila Vihar?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Dharmapala",
    "Option B": "Gopala",
    "Option C": "Nagpala",
    "Option D": "Mahipala",
    "Correct Ans": "Dharmapala"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following was the capital of Surasena Mahajanapada?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Viratnagar",
    "Option B": "Junagarh",
    "Option C": "Mathura",
    "Option D": "Kashi",
    "Correct Ans": "Mathura"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the author of Kitab-ul-Hind?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Abu Said",
    "Option B": "Abul Fazl",
    "Option C": "Firdausi",
    "Option D": "AI-Beruni",
    "Correct Ans": "AI-Beruni"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the founder leader of ‘Muslim Faqirs’ ?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Majnun Shah",
    "Option B": "Dadu Mian",
    "Option C": "Tipu",
    "Option D": "Chirag Ali Shah",
    "Correct Ans": "Majnun Shah"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is the author of \"Shah nama\"?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Utbi",
    "Option B": "Firdausi",
    "Option C": "Hasan Nizami",
    "Option D": "AI-Beruni",
    "Correct Ans": "Firdausi"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who among the following Sultans of Delhi introduced the token currency?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Balban",
    "Option B": "Alauddin Khalji",
    "Option C": "Muhammad bin Tughlaq",
    "Option D": "Firuz Tughlaq",
    "Correct Ans": "Muhammad bin Tughlaq"
  },
  {
    "Question": "After his coronation Shivaji assumed the title of",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Maharaja",
    "Option B": "Peshwa",
    "Option C": "Chhatrapati",
    "Option D": "Samrat",
    "Correct Ans": "Chhatrapati"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Akbar established Ibadat Khana at",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Lahore",
    "Option B": "Delhi",
    "Option C": "Agra",
    "Option D": "Fatehpur Sikri",
    "Correct Ans": "Fatehpur Sikri"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Sikh guru who compiled the Guru Granth Sahib was",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Nanak",
    "Option B": "Har Rai",
    "Option C": "Arjun",
    "Option D": "Bahadur",
    "Correct Ans": "Arjun"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Humayun Nama was written by",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Humayun",
    "Option B": "Mirza Kamran",
    "Option C": "Bairam Khan",
    "Option D": "Gulbadan Begum",
    "Correct Ans": "Gulbadan Begum"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the last Mughal emperor?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Shah Alam-II",
    "Option B": "Akbar-II",
    "Option C": "Bahadur Shah-II",
    "Option D": "Ahmad Shah",
    "Correct Ans": "Bahadur Shah-II"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Moti Masjid in the Red Fort, Delhi was constructed by",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Sher Shah",
    "Option B": "Shahjahan",
    "Option C": "Aurangzeb",
    "Option D": "Bhahadur Shah Zafar",
    "Correct Ans": "Aurangzeb"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who founded the Pala Empire?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Devapala",
    "Option B": "Dharmapala",
    "Option C": "Dhruva",
    "Option D": "Gopala",
    "Correct Ans": "Gopala"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the founder of the Sena dynasty?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Ballal Sena",
    "Option B": "Hemanta Sen",
    "Option C": "Lakshman Sen",
    "Option D": "Vijay Sen",
    "Correct Ans": "Hemanta Sen"
  },
  {
    "Question": "During the reign of which ruler Moroccan traveler Ibn Battuta visited India?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Aurangazeb",
    "Option B": "Akbar",
    "Option C": "Muhammad Bin Tughlaq",
    "Option D": "Alauddin Khilji",
    "Correct Ans": "Muhammad Bin Tughlaq"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Famous mosque Adhai Din Ka Jhonpra was built by which of the following ruler?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Qutub-ud-Din-Aibak",
    "Option B": "Muhammad Bin Tughlaq",
    "Option C": "Alauddin Khilji",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    "Correct Ans": "Qutub-ud-Din-Aibak"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Atala Masjid which was built by Sultan Ibrahim is located at?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Jaunpur",
    "Option B": "Kanpur",
    "Option C": "Agra",
    "Option D": "Mysore",
    "Correct Ans": "Jaunpur"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Hamza-nama paintings were produced during the reign of?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Humayun",
    "Option B": "Akbar",
    "Option C": "Jahangir",
    "Option D": "Shahjahan",
    "Correct Ans": "Akbar"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who built the famous Charminar of Hyderabad?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Krishndev Rai",
    "Option B": "Muhammad Quli Qutb Shah",
    "Option C": "Nadir Shah",
    "Option D": "Aurangzeb",
    "Correct Ans": "Muhammad Quli Qutb Shah"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which Sanskrit poet wrote famous book Geet Govinda?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Jayadeva",
    "Option B": "Kalidas",
    "Option C": "Panini",
    "Option D": "None of the above",
    "Correct Ans": "Jayadeva"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who built the Brihadeshwara Temple at Thanjavur?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Rajaraja Chola I",
    "Option B": "Vijayalaya Chola",
    "Option C": "Aditya Chola I",
    "Option D": "Rajendra Chola",
    "Correct Ans": "Rajaraja Chola I"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Atish Dipankar Srigyan was the abbot of -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Nalanda",
    "Option B": "Vikramashila",
    "Option C": "Somapura",
    "Option D": "Jagaddala",
    "Correct Ans": "Vikramashila"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Vikramshila mahavihar was situated in -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Bhagalpur",
    "Option B": "Dhaka",
    "Option C": "Rajshahi",
    "Option D": "Paharpur",
    "Correct Ans": "Bhagalpur"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the founder of the Chola dynasty?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Vijayalaya",
    "Option B": "Aditya I",
    "Option C": "Parantaka I",
    "Option D": "Rajraj I",
    "Correct Ans": "Vijayalaya"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who assumed the title of 'Gangaikondachola'?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Rajendra I",
    "Option B": "Rajaraja I",
    "Option C": "Rajadhiraja I",
    "Option D": "Kulotunga I",
    "Correct Ans": "Rajendra I"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the author of 'Shahnama'?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Utbi",
    "Option B": "Firdausi",
    "Option C": "Alberuni",
    "Option D": "Barni",
    "Correct Ans": "Firdausi"
  },
  {
    "Question": "When was the first battle of Tarain fought?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "1175 A.D.",
    "Option B": "1191 A.D.",
    "Option C": "1192 A.D.",
    "Option D": "1206 A.D.",
    "Correct Ans": "1191 A.D."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which king of Bengal was defeated by Bakhtiyar Khilji in the 13th century?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Mahipal",
    "Option B": "Lakshmanasen",
    "Option C": "Shashank",
    "Option D": "Grihavarman",
    "Correct Ans": "Lakshmanasen"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first turk to invade India?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Mohammad Ghori",
    "Option B": "Qutubuddin Aibak",
    "Option C": "Mohammad Bin Qasim",
    "Option D": "Muhammed Ghazni",
    "Correct Ans": "Muhammed Ghazni"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the only female ruler of Delhi Sultanate?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Chand Bibi",
    "Option B": "Noor Jahan",
    "Option C": "Razia Sultan",
    "Option D": "Mumtaz Mahal",
    "Correct Ans": "Razia Sultan"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the last ruler of Lodhi Dynasty?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Bahlol Lodhi",
    "Option B": "Ibrahim Lodhi",
    "Option C": "Sikandar Lodhi",
    "Option D": "Daulat Khan Lodhi",
    "Correct Ans": "Ibrahim Lodhi"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who among the following is known as Lakh Baksh in the Delhi sultanate?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Qutbuddin Aibak",
    "Option B": "Iltutmish",
    "Option C": "Alauddin Khalji",
    "Option D": "Ghiyasuddin Balban",
    "Correct Ans": "Qutbuddin Aibak"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Ibrahim Lodi fought with whom in the first battle of Panipat?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Babur",
    "Option B": "Balban",
    "Option C": "Maharana Pratap",
    "Option D": "Akbar",
    "Correct Ans": "Babur"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who founded Sayyid Dynasty?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Muhammad Shah",
    "Option B": "Bahram Shah",
    "Option C": "Khizr Khan",
    "Option D": "Alam Shah",
    "Correct Ans": "Khizr Khan"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who among the following Sultan constructed the famous Alai Darwaza?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Ziauddin Barani",
    "Option B": "Muhammad Bin Tughlaq",
    "Option C": "Alauddin Khalji",
    "Option D": "Ghiyasuddin Balban",
    "Correct Ans": "Alauddin Khalji"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Among the following, which Sultan founded the Khalji dynasty?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Qutbuddin",
    "Option B": "Jalaluddin Khalji",
    "Option C": "Alauddin Khalji",
    "Option D": "Ghazi Malik",
    "Correct Ans": "Jalaluddin Khalji"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was known as Ulugh Khan?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Qutbuddin Aibak",
    "Option B": "Bahlul Lodi",
    "Option C": "Alauddin Khalji",
    "Option D": "Ghiyasuddin Balban",
    "Correct Ans": "Ghiyasuddin Balban"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first European traveller to visit Vijayanagara?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Nicolo Conti",
    "Option B": "Abdur Razzaq",
    "Option C": "Athanasius Nikitin",
    "Option D": "Varthema",
    "Correct Ans": "Nicolo Conti"
  },
  {
    "Question": "When was the second battle of Panipat fought?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1556,
    "Option B": 1549,
    "Option C": 1578,
    "Option D": 1590,
    "Correct Ans": 1556
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who among the following Mughals made Fatehpur Sikri his new capital?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Alamgir",
    "Option B": "Bahadur Shah",
    "Option C": "Akbar",
    "Option D": "Muhammad Shah",
    "Correct Ans": "Akbar"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In which year the battle of Haldighati was fought?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1578,
    "Option B": 1571,
    "Option C": 1576,
    "Option D": 1575,
    "Correct Ans": 1576
  },
  {
    "Question": "Between Mughal and Whom, the Battle of Haldighati was fought?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Rana Sanga",
    "Option B": "Hemu",
    "Option C": "Rana Pratap Singh",
    "Option D": "Adil Shah",
    "Correct Ans": "Rana Pratap Singh"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who wrote Akbar Nama?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Abul Fazl",
    "Option B": "Firdawsi",
    "Option C": "Utbi",
    "Option D": "Naziri",
    "Correct Ans": "Abul Fazl"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the Sikh Guru executed by Aurangzeb?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Guru Har Rai",
    "Option B": "Guru Govind Singh",
    "Option C": "Guru Angad",
    "Option D": "Guru Tegh Bahadur",
    "Correct Ans": "Guru Tegh Bahadur"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who among the following Mughals built the Red fort of Delhi?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Humayun",
    "Option B": "Babur",
    "Option C": "Shah Jahan",
    "Option D": "Aurangzeb",
    "Correct Ans": "Shah Jahan"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who defeated Humayun in the battle of Chausa?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Muhammad Adil Shah",
    "Option B": "Firoz Shah Suri",
    "Option C": "Sikandar Shah Suri",
    "Option D": "Sher Shah Suri",
    "Correct Ans": "Sher Shah Suri"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The original name of Tansen, the greatest musician of the court of Akbar, was",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Makaranda Pandey",
    "Option B": "Ramatanu Pande",
    "Option C": "Haridas",
    "Option D": "Lal Kalawant",
    "Correct Ans": "Ramatanu Pande"
  },
  {
    "Question": "During Akbar's reign who was the Finance Minister of the Mughal empire?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Raja Todar Mal",
    "Option B": "Man Singh-I",
    "Option C": "Birbal",
    "Option D": "Tansen",
    "Correct Ans": "Raja Todar Mal"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first Sikh guru?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Guru Arjun Singh",
    "Option B": "Guru Teg Bahadur",
    "Option C": "Guru Govind Singh",
    "Option D": "Guru Nanak",
    "Correct Ans": "Guru Nanak"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Amir Khusro was disciple of which sufi saint ?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Moinuddin Chisti",
    "Option B": "Sheikh Nizamuddin Aulia",
    "Option C": "Hamiduddin Naguri",
    "Option D": "Sheikh Kutubuddin Bakhtiyar",
    "Correct Ans": "Sheikh Nizamuddin Aulia"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who of the following established chishti sufi order in India?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Khwaja Badruddin",
    "Option B": "Khwaja Moinuddin",
    "Option C": "Shekh Ahmad Sarhindi",
    "Option D": "Shekh Bahauddin Jakariya",
    "Correct Ans": "Khwaja Moinuddin"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Aurangzeb was son of -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Babur",
    "Option B": "Shah Jahan",
    "Option C": "Jahangir",
    "Option D": "Akbar",
    "Correct Ans": "Shah Jahan"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Razmnama' was the persian translation of -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Ramayan",
    "Option B": "Upanishad",
    "Option C": "Mahabharat",
    "Option D": "Geeta",
    "Correct Ans": "Mahabharat"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Chaitanya Mahaprabhu was native of",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Assam",
    "Option B": "Bangladesh",
    "Option C": "Bengal",
    "Option D": "Bihar",
    "Correct Ans": "Bengal"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Khalsa Panth was founded by",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Guru Gobind Singh",
    "Option B": "Guru Ramdas",
    "Option C": "Guru Nanak",
    "Option D": "Arjun Dev",
    "Correct Ans": "Guru Gobind Singh"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was known as 'Alamgir'?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Shah Jahan",
    "Option B": "Aurangjeb",
    "Option C": "Akbar",
    "Option D": "Babur",
    "Correct Ans": "Aurangjeb"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The ‘Treaty of Purandar’ was signed between :-",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Akbar and Rana Pratap",
    "Option B": "Jai Singh and Shivaji",
    "Option C": "Aurangzeb and Sahu",
    "Option D": "Jai Singh and Golkunda",
    "Correct Ans": "Jai Singh and Shivaji"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Jijya was abolished by -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Babur",
    "Option B": "Humayun",
    "Option C": "Jahangir",
    "Option D": "Akbar",
    "Correct Ans": "Akbar"
  },
  {
    "Question": "When did Aurangjeb die?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1702,
    "Option B": 1707,
    "Option C": 1709,
    "Option D": 1701,
    "Correct Ans": 1707
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who built the Grand Trunk Road?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Akbar",
    "Option B": "Shah Jahan",
    "Option C": "Sher Shah",
    "Option D": "Babur",
    "Correct Ans": "Sher Shah"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In which year, Shivaji was crowned as the Chhatrapati?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1675,
    "Option B": 1677,
    "Option C": 1674,
    "Option D": 1670,
    "Correct Ans": 1674
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following was adopted by Lord Dalhousie to annex Indian states?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Rowlatt Act",
    "Option B": "The Doctrine of Lapse",
    "Option C": "Policy of Subsidiary Alliance",
    "Option D": "Permanent Settlement of land revenue",
    "Correct Ans": "The Doctrine of Lapse"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The battle of Buxar took place in",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1764,
    "Option B": 1766,
    "Option C": 1763,
    "Option D": 1768,
    "Correct Ans": 1764
  },
  {
    "Question": "In which year did the \"Battle of Plassey\" take place?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1756,
    "Option B": 1757,
    "Option C": 1751,
    "Option D": 1759,
    "Correct Ans": 1757
  },
  {
    "Question": "The first British Presidency in India was established at",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Madras",
    "Option B": "Surat",
    "Option C": "Calcutta",
    "Option D": "Delhi",
    "Correct Ans": "Surat"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first Governor General of India?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Warren Hastings",
    "Option B": "William Bentick",
    "Option C": "Lord Delhousie",
    "Option D": "Lord Canning",
    "Correct Ans": "Warren Hastings"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The first Viceroy of India was",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Lord Canning",
    "Option B": "Lord Hardinge",
    "Option C": "Lord Dalhousie",
    "Option D": "Lord Elgin",
    "Correct Ans": "Lord Canning"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Indian naval mutiny against the British took place in the year",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1857,
    "Option B": 1846,
    "Option C": 1946,
    "Option D": 1947,
    "Correct Ans": 1946
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Treaty of Lahore was signed between the Sikhs and the British in India in the year",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1836,
    "Option B": 1846,
    "Option C": 1845,
    "Option D": 1840,
    "Correct Ans": 1846
  },
  {
    "Question": "Rani Laxmi Bai died fighting the British in the Battle of",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Jhansi",
    "Option B": "Kanpur",
    "Option C": "Gwalior",
    "Option D": "Kalpi",
    "Correct Ans": "Jhansi"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Gandhiji’s famous Quit India movement call to the British was given in",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1943,
    "Option B": 1941,
    "Option C": 1942,
    "Option D": 1945,
    "Correct Ans": 1942
  },
  {
    "Question": "Vasco Da Gama arrived in India in -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1495,
    "Option B": 1489,
    "Option C": 1498,
    "Option D": 1499,
    "Correct Ans": 1498
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Treaty of Mangalore was in the year",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1584,
    "Option B": 1784,
    "Option C": 1788,
    "Option D": 1588,
    "Correct Ans": 1784
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was responsible for the Jallianwala Bagh Massacre of 1919 ?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Officer Saunders",
    "Option B": "General Dyer",
    "Option C": "Lord Curzon",
    "Option D": "Lord Hunter",
    "Correct Ans": "General Dyer"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Vernacular Press Act was passed in -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1877,
    "Option B": 1868,
    "Option C": 1878,
    "Option D": 1867,
    "Correct Ans": 1878
  },
  {
    "Question": "When the Simon Commission visited India the Viceroy was",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Lloyd George",
    "Option B": "Lord Irwin",
    "Option C": "Lord Reading",
    "Option D": "Lord Ripon",
    "Correct Ans": "Lord Irwin"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In which year was Gandhi-Irwin Pact signed?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1928,
    "Option B": 1931,
    "Option C": 1932,
    "Option D": 1929,
    "Correct Ans": 1931
  },
  {
    "Question": "When did Sepoy mutiny start?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1856,
    "Option B": 1857,
    "Option C": 1858,
    "Option D": 1859,
    "Correct Ans": 1857
  },
  {
    "Question": "When did the Santhal rebellion start?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1856,
    "Option B": 1853,
    "Option C": 1855,
    "Option D": 1857,
    "Correct Ans": 1855
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who led the Santhal uprising?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Sidhu and Kanhu",
    "Option B": "Birsa Munda",
    "Option C": "Tana Bhagat",
    "Option D": "Titumir",
    "Correct Ans": "Sidhu and Kanhu"
  },
  {
    "Question": "When did Bastar Rebellion in central India break out?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1909,
    "Option B": 1910,
    "Option C": 1911,
    "Option D": 1912,
    "Correct Ans": 1910
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the leader of the Munda Rebellion?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Birsa Munda",
    "Option B": "Raghava Munda",
    "Option C": "Sidhu Munda",
    "Option D": "Kanhu Munda",
    "Correct Ans": "Birsa Munda"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who wrote 'Nil Darpan'?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Ramratan Mallick",
    "Option B": "Dinabandhu Mitra",
    "Option C": "Kaliprasanna Singha",
    "Option D": "Mir Nishar Ali",
    "Correct Ans": "Dinabandhu Mitra"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Indian League' was founded in -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1876,
    "Option B": 1875,
    "Option C": 1877,
    "Option D": 1879,
    "Correct Ans": 1875
  },
  {
    "Question": "Vande Mataram' is part of -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Kapalkundala",
    "Option B": "Anandamath",
    "Option C": "Rajasimha",
    "Option D": "Bankim Rachanabali",
    "Correct Ans": "Anandamath"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Moplah rebellion of 1921 broke out in",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Bengal",
    "Option B": "Kerala",
    "Option C": "Tamilnadu",
    "Option D": "Punjab",
    "Correct Ans": "Kerala"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first woman to participate in the Civil Disobedience Movement?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Matangini Hazra",
    "Option B": "Sarojini Naidu",
    "Option C": "Indira Gandhi",
    "Option D": "Vijay Lakshmi Pandit",
    "Correct Ans": "Sarojini Naidu"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The first Trade Union of India -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Bombay Labour Union",
    "Option B": "Madras Labour Union",
    "Option C": "Surat Labour Union",
    "Option D": "Calcutta Labour Union",
    "Correct Ans": "Madras Labour Union"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The 'Chauri Chaura Incident' took place during -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Civil Disobedience movement",
    "Option B": "Non-cooperation movement",
    "Option C": "Quit India movement",
    "Option D": "Navy mutiny",
    "Correct Ans": "Non-cooperation movement"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In which year Communist Party of India was formed?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": 1920,
    "Option B": 1921,
    "Option C": 1919,
    "Option D": 1923,
    "Correct Ans": 1920
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is popularly knowns as 'Master Da' ?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Anant Singh",
    "Option B": "Ganesh Ghosh",
    "Option C": "Surya Sen",
    "Option D": "Badal Das",
    "Correct Ans": "Surya Sen"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the youngest revolutionary freedom fighter who opposed British Raj in India?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Prafulla Chaki",
    "Option B": "Bina Das",
    "Option C": "Bhagat Singh",
    "Option D": "Khudiram Bose",
    "Correct Ans": "Khudiram Bose"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Bhagat Singh was executed in which of the following case?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Lahore conspiracy case",
    "Option B": "Central Assembly bomb case",
    "Option C": "Kakori case",
    "Option D": "Dalhousie square bomb case",
    "Correct Ans": "Lahore conspiracy case"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who killed N.S. Simpson ?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Binay Badal Dinesh",
    "Option B": "Khudiram Bose",
    "Option C": "Surya Sen",
    "Option D": "Bhagat Singh",
    "Correct Ans": "Binay Badal Dinesh"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Alluri Sitaram Raju was associated with -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Mophala movement",
    "Option B": "Rampa Rebellion",
    "Option C": "Gond uprising",
    "Option D": "Koli uprising",
    "Correct Ans": "Rampa Rebellion"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who gave the slogan 'Delhi Chalo'?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Bhagat Singh",
    "Option B": "Mahatma Gandhi",
    "Option C": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
    "Option D": "Jawharlal Neheru",
    "Correct Ans": "Subhas Chandra Bose"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first commander-in-chief of the Indian National Army?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Mohan Singh",
    "Option B": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
    "Option C": "Rash Behai Bose",
    "Option D": "Shah Nawaz Khan",
    "Correct Ans": "Mohan Singh"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who declared the Communal Award in 1932?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Jinnah",
    "Option B": "Lord Mountbatten",
    "Option C": "Ramsay Macdonald",
    "Option D": "Syed Ahmed",
    "Correct Ans": "Ramsay Macdonald"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The first Home Minister of India -",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
    "Option B": "Jawharlal Nehru",
    "Option C": "V.K. Menon",
    "Option D": "Abul Kalam Azad",
    "Correct Ans": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the Nizam of Hydrabad during 1946-47?",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "Najm-ud-daula",
    "Option B": "mubarak ud daulah",
    "Option C": "Kashim Rizvi",
    "Option D": "Mir Osman Ali Khan",
    "Correct Ans": "Mir Osman Ali Khan"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Constitution of India was adopted on",
    "Subtopic": "Indian History",
    "Option A": "26 January, 1950",
    "Option B": "26 January, 1949",
    "Option C": "26 November, 1950",
    "Option D": "26 November, 1949",
    "Correct Ans": "26 November, 1949"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which civilisation is the oldest in the world?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Egyptian Civilization",
    "Option B": "Mesopotamian Civilization",
    "Option C": "Chinese Civilization",
    "Option D": "Indus Valley Civilization",
    "Correct Ans": "Mesopotamian Civilization"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is known as the father of History?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Sophocles",
    "Option B": "Homer",
    "Option C": "Herodotus",
    "Option D": "Aristophanes",
    "Correct Ans": "Herodotus"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Industrial Revolution started in?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": 1760,
    "Option B": 1764,
    "Option C": 1761,
    "Option D": 1762,
    "Correct Ans": 1760
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where did the Industrial Revolution first start?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Great Britain",
    "Option B": "France",
    "Option C": "Rome",
    "Option D": "America",
    "Correct Ans": "Great Britain"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which year did Christopher Columbus discover America?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": 1490,
    "Option B": 1492,
    "Option C": 1491,
    "Option D": 1494,
    "Correct Ans": 1492
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the duration of the French Revolution?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "1788 – 1792",
    "Option B": "1789 – 1799",
    "Option C": "1789 – 1799",
    "Option D": "1781 – 1790",
    "Correct Ans": "1789 – 1799"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Whose reign was the king during the French Revolution?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Louis XVI",
    "Option B": "Louis XV",
    "Option C": "Napoleon",
    "Option D": "Louis XIV",
    "Correct Ans": "Louis XVI"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the revolutionary behind the Unification of Italy?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Guiseppe Garibaldi",
    "Option B": "Victor Emmanuel II",
    "Option C": "Felice Orsini",
    "Option D": "Victor Emmanuel III",
    "Correct Ans": "Guiseppe Garibaldi"
  },
  {
    "Question": "When did World War I start?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "July 28, 1914",
    "Option B": "July 28, 1915",
    "Option C": "July 25, 1914",
    "Option D": "July 28, 1920",
    "Correct Ans": "July 28, 1914"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the policy used by Bismark during the Unification of Germany?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Blood and Iron",
    "Option B": "Blood and Sweat",
    "Option C": "Iron and Steel",
    "Option D": "Patriotism and Blood",
    "Correct Ans": "Blood and Iron"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which nation was standing neutral during the First World War?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Italy",
    "Option B": "Germany",
    "Option C": "Prussia",
    "Option D": "Norway",
    "Correct Ans": "Norway"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Second World War started",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "September 1939",
    "Option B": "September 1930",
    "Option C": "September 1937",
    "Option D": "September 1938",
    "Correct Ans": "September 1939"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The first-ever president appointed in the United States of America was?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "George Washington",
    "Option B": "Theodore Roosevelt",
    "Option C": "Abraham Lincoln",
    "Option D": "Thomas Jefferson",
    "Correct Ans": "George Washington"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the immediate cause of the beginning of the First World War?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "The murder of William I",
    "Option B": "The murder of Archduke Ferdinand",
    "Option C": "The murder of Victor Emmanuel II",
    "Option D": "The murder of William II",
    "Correct Ans": "The murder of Archduke Ferdinand"
  },
  {
    "Question": "When was the start of the Russian Revolution?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": 1919,
    "Option B": 1918,
    "Option C": 1915,
    "Option D": 1917,
    "Correct Ans": 1917
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who presided as the King during the Russian Revolution?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Nicholas II",
    "Option B": "Alexander III",
    "Option C": "Nicholas I",
    "Option D": "Alexander II",
    "Correct Ans": "Nicholas II"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who was the first president of the Republic of China?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Sun Yat-Sen",
    "Option B": "Yuan Shik-Kai",
    "Option C": "Chiang Kai-Shek",
    "Option D": "Li Yuan-Hong",
    "Correct Ans": "Sun Yat-Sen"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Who is known as the founder of Modern Turkey?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Mustafa Kemal Pasha",
    "Option B": "Celal Bayar",
    "Option C": "Ismet Inonu",
    "Option D": "Cemal Gursel",
    "Correct Ans": "Mustafa Kemal Pasha"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What was the ultimate cause of the Second World War?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Invasion of Prussia",
    "Option B": "Invasion of Austria",
    "Option C": "Invasion of Poland",
    "Option D": "Invasion of Italy",
    "Correct Ans": "Invasion of Poland"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Great Wall of China was made during the reign of which of the following ruler?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "King Zhuangxiang",
    "Option B": "Qin Shi Huang",
    "Option C": "Qin Er Shi",
    "Option D": "Chongzhen",
    "Correct Ans": "Qin Shi Huang"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In which year did the Boston Tea Party take place?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": 1773,
    "Option B": 1776,
    "Option C": 1774,
    "Option D": 1775,
    "Correct Ans": 1773
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Hundred Year's war was fought between which two countries?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "England and France",
    "Option B": "England and Italy",
    "Option C": "England and Germany",
    "Option D": "Germany and France",
    "Correct Ans": "England and France"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Soviet Union broke down in the year",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": 1991,
    "Option B": 1990,
    "Option C": 1992,
    "Option D": 1989,
    "Correct Ans": 1991
  },
  {
    "Question": "Hitler was the dictator of which country?",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "France",
    "Option B": "Italy",
    "Option C": "Germany",
    "Option D": "England",
    "Correct Ans": "Germany"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The attack by the third estate on the Bastille prison sparked the",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "Russian Revolution",
    "Option B": "French Revolution",
    "Option C": "Break up of Soviet Union",
    "Option D": "The fall of Tsar",
    "Correct Ans": "French Revolution"
  },
  {
    "Question": "During the First World War, which country signed the Peace Treaty (1917) with Germany",
    "Subtopic": "World History",
    "Option A": "England",
    "Option B": "USA",
    "Option C": "Soviet Russia",
    "Option D": "Austria",
    "Correct Ans": "Soviet Russia"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where is the deepest mine in the world located?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "South America",
    "Option B": "South Africa",
    "Option C": "South India",
    "Option D": "South Australia",
    "Correct Ans": "South America"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The upper most layer of the earth’s surface is called",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "crust",
    "Option B": "mantle",
    "Option C": "core",
    "Option D": "silica",
    "Correct Ans": "crust"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the radius of the earth?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "3671 km",
    "Option B": "7163 km",
    "Option C": "6371 km",
    "Option D": "1736 km",
    "Correct Ans": "6371 km"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Tropic of Capricorn is located at",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "23.5° N",
    "Option B": "23.5° S",
    "Option C": "66.5° N",
    "Option D": "66.5° S",
    "Correct Ans": "23.5° S"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Direct rays of the sun fall on the equator on",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "21 March",
    "Option B": "22 December",
    "Option C": "23 August",
    "Option D": "21 June",
    "Correct Ans": "21 March"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The number of days in a leap year is",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": 365,
    "Option B": 366,
    "Option C": 364,
    "Option D": 367,
    "Correct Ans": 366
  },
  {
    "Question": "The deepest point in the earth is",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "The Bermuda Triangle",
    "Option B": "The Dead Sea",
    "Option C": "The Challenger Deep",
    "Option D": "The Survivor Deep",
    "Correct Ans": "The Challenger Deep"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The thinnest layer of earth is",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "crust",
    "Option B": "mantle",
    "Option C": "core",
    "Option D": "silica",
    "Correct Ans": "crust"
  },
  {
    "Question": "An example of metamorphic rock is",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Granite",
    "Option B": "Basalt",
    "Option C": "Limestone",
    "Option D": "Marble",
    "Correct Ans": "Marble"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Ox bow lakes are found in:",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Glaciers",
    "Option B": "River valleys",
    "Option C": "Deserts",
    "Option D": "Beach",
    "Correct Ans": "River valleys"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following layers of the atmosphere is free from clouds?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Troposphere",
    "Option B": "Stratosphere",
    "Option C": "Mesosphere",
    "Option D": "Thermosphere",
    "Correct Ans": "Stratosphere"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the followings is the local wind in the rockies mountains?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Khamsin",
    "Option B": "Siroco",
    "Option C": "Chinook",
    "Option D": "Bora",
    "Correct Ans": "Chinook"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Tropical storm in Chinese Sea is known as:",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Cyclone",
    "Option B": "Tornadoes",
    "Option C": "Typhoons",
    "Option D": "Hurricanes",
    "Correct Ans": "Typhoons"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following, is a landlocked sea?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Timor Sea",
    "Option B": "Arafura Sea",
    "Option C": "Greeland Sea",
    "Option D": "Aral Sea",
    "Correct Ans": "Aral Sea"
  },
  {
    "Question": "A place where there is constant intermingling of salt water and fresh water is:",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Estuary",
    "Option B": "Delta",
    "Option C": "Gulf",
    "Option D": "Bay",
    "Correct Ans": "Estuary"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Isobars are lines joining places having equal:",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Rainfall",
    "Option B": "Pressure",
    "Option C": "Height",
    "Option D": "temperature",
    "Correct Ans": "Pressure"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Tropical grassland of Brazil is called:",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Campos",
    "Option B": "Pampas",
    "Option C": "Prairies",
    "Option D": "Savannah",
    "Correct Ans": "Campos"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Shale is metamorphosed into which of the following rocks?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Graphite",
    "Option B": "Gneiss",
    "Option C": "Marble",
    "Option D": "Slate",
    "Correct Ans": "Slate"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which one of the following planets has no moon?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Mars",
    "Option B": "Earth",
    "Option C": "Saturn",
    "Option D": "Mercury",
    "Correct Ans": "Mercury"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Dolomite is a/an",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Sedimentary rock",
    "Option B": "Plutonic rock",
    "Option C": "Igneous rock",
    "Option D": "Metamorphic rock",
    "Correct Ans": "Sedimentary rock"
  },
  {
    "Question": "El Nino is:",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "a warm ocean current",
    "Option B": "sea storm",
    "Option C": "tropical disturbance",
    "Option D": "another name of typhoon",
    "Correct Ans": "a warm ocean current"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Colca Canyon is located in which country?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "USA",
    "Option B": "Chile",
    "Option C": "Peru",
    "Option D": "Mexico",
    "Correct Ans": "Peru"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The landform named ‘meander’ is created by a",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Volcano",
    "Option B": "Sea",
    "Option C": "River",
    "Option D": "Wind",
    "Correct Ans": "River"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The fastest moving glacier is -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Siachen",
    "Option B": "Volta",
    "Option C": "Lambert",
    "Option D": "Jakobshavn",
    "Correct Ans": "Jakobshavn"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which country is known as 'The land of fjords' -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Iceland",
    "Option B": "Finland",
    "Option C": "Norway",
    "Option D": "Canada",
    "Correct Ans": "Norway"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Where is the Great Basin desert located?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "USA",
    "Option B": "Peru",
    "Option C": "Australia",
    "Option D": "South Africa",
    "Correct Ans": "USA"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which landform is known as 'Mushroom rocks'?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Yardang",
    "Option B": "Zeugen",
    "Option C": "Inselbergs",
    "Option D": "gour",
    "Correct Ans": "gour"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Salt lakes in Sahara desert is known as -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Chott",
    "Option B": "Bolson",
    "Option C": "Dhand",
    "Option D": "Tal",
    "Correct Ans": "Chott"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Radio wave is reflected from -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Mesosphere",
    "Option B": "Ionosphere",
    "Option C": "Exosphere",
    "Option D": "Troposphere",
    "Correct Ans": "Ionosphere"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which instrument is used measure the humidity of air?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Thermometer",
    "Option B": "Barometer",
    "Option C": "Hygrometer",
    "Option D": "Anemometer",
    "Correct Ans": "Hygrometer"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which is known as 'Trade wind' -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Westerlies",
    "Option B": "Polar Easterlies",
    "Option C": "Tropical Easterlies",
    "Option D": "Monsoon wind",
    "Correct Ans": "Tropical Easterlies"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which type of rainfall occurs in Equatorial region?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Convectional rainfall",
    "Option B": "Orographic rainfall",
    "Option C": "Tropical cyclonic rainfall",
    "Option D": "Subtropical cyclonic rainfall",
    "Correct Ans": "Convectional rainfall"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which climate region is known as 'Resort Climate of the world'?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Tropical",
    "Option B": "Polar",
    "Option C": "Mediterranean",
    "Option D": "Equatorial",
    "Correct Ans": "Mediterranean"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Example of cold ocean current -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "North Atlantic Current",
    "Option B": "Kuroshio Current",
    "Option C": "Labrador Current",
    "Option D": "Gulf Stream",
    "Correct Ans": "Labrador Current"
  },
  {
    "Question": "‘Sargasso Sea’ is found in the centre of",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Pacific Ocean",
    "Option B": "Atlantic Ocean",
    "Option C": "Arctic Ocean",
    "Option D": "Indian Ocean",
    "Correct Ans": "Atlantic Ocean"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The local wind of Adriatic coast is -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Mistral",
    "Option B": "Bora",
    "Option C": "Chinook",
    "Option D": "Pampero",
    "Correct Ans": "Bora"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the followings is a warm local wind?",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Foehn",
    "Option B": "Bora",
    "Option C": "Mistral",
    "Option D": "Pampero",
    "Correct Ans": "Foehn"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The earth is at the largest distance from sun on -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "21st June",
    "Option B": "3rd January",
    "Option C": "4th July",
    "Option D": "23rd September",
    "Correct Ans": "4th July"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Geostationary orbit is at a height of -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "3600 km",
    "Option B": "1000 km",
    "Option C": "36000 km",
    "Option D": "10000 km",
    "Correct Ans": "36000 km"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Marble is a metamorphic rock of -",
    "Subtopic": "Physical Geography",
    "Option A": "Sandstone",
    "Option B": "Limestone",
    "Option C": "Granite",
    "Option D": "Clay",
    "Correct Ans": "Limestone"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The origin of Danube river -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Black Forest",
    "Option B": "Vosges",
    "Option C": "Alps",
    "Option D": "Ural",
    "Correct Ans": "Black Forest"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The largest industrial region of",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "London",
    "Option B": "Ruhr",
    "Option C": "Paris",
    "Option D": "Lisbon",
    "Correct Ans": "Ruhr"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Ruhr industrial region is situated in -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "England",
    "Option B": "Germany",
    "Option C": "Nederlands",
    "Option D": "France",
    "Correct Ans": "Germany"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which mountain range separates Europe and Asia?",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Alps",
    "Option B": "Ural",
    "Option C": "Jura",
    "Option D": "Pyrenees",
    "Correct Ans": "Ural"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The famous active volcano 'Mount Etna' is located in which country?",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Japan",
    "Option B": "Indonesia",
    "Option C": "Italy",
    "Option D": "USA",
    "Correct Ans": "Italy"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which is the longest river that flows through France?",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Rhone",
    "Option B": "Loire",
    "Option C": "Seine",
    "Option D": "Garrone",
    "Correct Ans": "Loire"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which is the highest mountain peak in the Alps mountain?",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Mont Blanc",
    "Option B": "Mount Elgon",
    "Option C": "Mount Speke",
    "Option D": "Socompa",
    "Correct Ans": "Mont Blanc"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Polder is the reclaimed lands of",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Netherlands",
    "Option B": "Germany",
    "Option C": "Scotland",
    "Option D": "France",
    "Correct Ans": "Netherlands"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The longest river of china is -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Yangtze River",
    "Option B": "Hoang ho river",
    "Option C": "Lena river",
    "Option D": "Amur river",
    "Correct Ans": "Yangtze River"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Kirkuk oilfield is situated in -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Iraq",
    "Option B": "Iran",
    "Option C": "Saudi Arabia",
    "Option D": "Qatar",
    "Correct Ans": "Iraq"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which is the largest fresh water lake in the World?",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Baikal",
    "Option B": "Victoria",
    "Option C": "Superior",
    "Option D": "Erie",
    "Correct Ans": "Baikal"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which plateau is known as the \"Roof of the World\"?",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Deccan plateau",
    "Option B": "Pamir plateau",
    "Option C": "Khorat plateau",
    "Option D": "Katanga plateau",
    "Correct Ans": "Pamir plateau"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The largest desert of Asia is -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Gobi",
    "Option B": "Thar",
    "Option C": "Arabian",
    "Option D": "Atakama",
    "Correct Ans": "Gobi"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The tropical grassland of Africa is known as -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Prairies",
    "Option B": "Savannah",
    "Option C": "Taiga",
    "Option D": "Veld",
    "Correct Ans": "Savannah"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The longest river in the world -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Nile",
    "Option B": "Amazon",
    "Option C": "Ganga",
    "Option D": "Yangtze",
    "Correct Ans": "Nile"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Victoria Falls are one the river -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Nile",
    "Option B": "Congo",
    "Option C": "Zambezi",
    "Option D": "Niger",
    "Correct Ans": "Zambezi"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The heighest mountain peak of Africa is -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Mount Kilimanjaro",
    "Option B": "Mount Kenya",
    "Option C": "Mount Stanley",
    "Option D": "Mount Speke",
    "Correct Ans": "Mount Kilimanjaro"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The largest nation of Africa is -",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Sudan",
    "Option B": "Algeria",
    "Option C": "Libya",
    "Option D": "Niger",
    "Correct Ans": "Algeria"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which is the longest Freshwater lake in the world?",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Lake Kariba",
    "Option B": "Lake Albert",
    "Option C": "Lake Tanganyika",
    "Option D": "Lake Victoria",
    "Correct Ans": "Lake Tanganyika"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The second longest river in Africa?",
    "Subtopic": "World Geography",
    "Option A": "Nile",
    "Option B": "Congo",
    "Option C": "Orange",
    "Option D": "Zambezi",
    "Correct Ans": "Congo"
  }
]